Guide to the Arthur Davison Ficke Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1895-1959; Series II; 9.75; (25 boxes)
  - GLADYS BROWN FICKE
    - Books
      - "The Poetry and Philosophy of Chinese Landscape Painting"
        - Index: typescript, corrected, original draft, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1244)
        - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 40, Folder 1245)
        - Photographs, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1246)
      - ["The Village"]: holograph and typescript, corrected, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 1247)
    - Miscellaneous writings
      - Notes
        - Notebook, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1248)
        - Notes: holograph and typescript, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1249-1252)
        - [André] Malraux: holograph and typescript (Box 40, Folder 1253)
        - Anna Freud; holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1254)
        - [Bertrand Russell]: holograph (Box 40, Folder 1255)
        - Carl Jung: holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1256)
        - "Considerations Psychoanalytiques...": by Jean-Frois- Wittenassn, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1257)
        - "Devant la Barrière...": by René Lafargue, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1258)
        - E.R. Goodenough: holograph and printed material (Box 40, Folder 1259)
        - "Eléments d'une...": by Pierre Klossowski, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1260)
        - George Santayana: holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1261)
        - "Hamlet and Oedipus": by Ernest Jones, holograph (Box 40, Folder 1262)
        - [Jung and Others]: holograph (Box 40, Folder 1263)
        - "Le Role des Zones...": by W. Bischler, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1264)
        - "Metapsychology of Artistic Creator": by Gustav Bychowski, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1265)
        - "The Moral Judgement of the Child": holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1266)
        - "On Psychoanalytic Theory of Affects": by David Rapaport, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1267)
        - [Persons and Places]: holograph (Box 40, Folder 1268)
        - "The Psychoanalyst and the Artist": by[?] Scheider, holograph (Box 40, Folder 1269)
        - Sigmund Freud: holograph and typescript (Box 40, Folder 1270-1271)
        - "Young Man Luther": by E. Erikson, holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1272)
      - Plays
        - "For Tomorrow We Die": typescript, original, n.d (Box 40, Folder 1273)
          With TL [transcript] to "Miss Rice" from Maurice Crain, 1940 Apr 9.
        - "For Tomorrow We Die": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1274)
          With a note by Arthur Davison Ficke.
      - Poetry
        - "Alone": typescript, original, signed, 1950 May (Box 41, Folder 1275)
        - "An Undertaking": typescript, original, signed, 1950 May
        - "The Analyst": typescript, original, 1954 Nov 7
        - "Darkness": typescript, original, signed, 1950 Aug 30
        - "Detained": typescript, original, signed, 1950 Jul 28
        - "Down There": typescript, original, 1963 Oct
        - "Escape": typescript, original, signed, 1950 Aug 7 (Box 41, Folder 1276)
        - "Free": typescript, original, 1950 Sep 29
        - "Helianthus": typescript, original, 1953 May 8
        - "Hermit": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d.
        - "Immersion": typescript, original, signed, and carbon (3 copies), 1949 Sep
        - "In the Beginning There Was No Word": typescript, carbon, 1953 Nov 10
        - "In the Dark": holograph, and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1950 Oct 29 (Box 41, Folder 1277)
        - "In Imitation of the Master": typescript, original, n.d.
        - "Jealousy": typescript, carbon, 1950 Nov 7
        - "The Machine Age": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d.
        - "The Mirror": typescript, original, 1950 Dec 23 (Box 41, Folder 1278)
        - "Possession": typescript, original, corrected, n.d.
        - "Reculde": holograph and typescript, corrected
        - "The Rose": typescript, original, corrected, and carbon (3 copies), 1953 Dec 10
        - "Saved": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1950 Oct 5 (Box 41, Folder 1279)
        - "Strange Dishes": typescript, original, signed, 1949 Aug 2
        - "The Time is Lost": typescript, original, 1951 Mar 18
        - "These Hills": typescript, original, n.d.
        - "To the Medicine Man": typescript, original, 1950 Jul
        - "What Dost Thou, Love": typescript, original (2 copies), 1953 May
        - "You Would Be Dreaming": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon, 1953 Nov 27-28
        - Untitled poem: holograph, 1934-35 (Box 41, Folder 1281)
        - Untitled poem: holograph, typescript (2 copies), 1945
        - Untitled poem: holograph, n.d.
        - Untitled poem: typescript, n.d.
      - Short stories
        - "[Aversions?]": holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1282)
        - "A Colt Named Daniel...": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1283)
        - "Compassion": typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 1284)
          With TLS to Gladys Brown Ficke from Witter Bynner, n.d.
        - "Eavesdropping": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1285)
        - "His Eldest Son": fragments, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 41, Folder 1286)
        - "His Eldest Son": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon (4 copies) (Box 41, Folder 1287)
        - "Hughes": holograph, with notes, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1288)
        - "On the Beach": holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1289)
        - "Spanish Adventure": by Augusta Brown [Gladys Brown Ficke], holograph, and typescript, original, corrected (Box 41, Folder 1290)
        - "Story": holograph, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1291)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Adams, Leonie
      - "Dark Rock the Wind is Worn": holograph and typescript, carbon (Box 42, Folder 1292)
    - Brooke, Rupert
      - "The Hill": holograph., 1914 (Box 42, Folder 1293)
        With: photograph taken by Eugene Hutchinson
    - Brown, Wolstan Crocker
      - "By the Sea": typescript, carbon, 1960 Apr 29 (Box 42, Folder 1294)
    - Browne, Maurice
      - "A Note on Arthur Davison Ficke": typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, 1947 May 25 (Box 42, Folder 1295)
      - "Paeon Past Death": holograph, typescript, original and carbon (3 copies), [ca. 1945] (Box 42, Folder 1296)
      - "Silence of the Night": typescript, carbon, 1916 Aug 3 (Box 42, Folder 1297)
      - "A Very Bad Sonnet...": holograph, 1931 Sep 19
    - Bynner, Witter
      - "Bed-Time Story": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 1298)
      - "Handmaid": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1940] (Box 42, Folder 1299)
      - "The Heart": typescript, original, [ca. 1940]
      - "Lunatic": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1940]
      - "O Hunted Huntress": holograph, corrected, signed, [1938?] (Box 42, Folder 1300)
      - "A 1921 Letter to an Inquiring Stranger": reprint, signed, 1960
      - "Thinking Rock": typescript, original, corrected, signed, [ca. 1940] (Box 42, Folder 1302)
      - "Vale Atque Ave.": typescript, original, [ca. 1940]
      - "Willow Mist": typescript, carbon, corrected, [ca. 1940]
    - Dell, Floyd
      - "A Note on the Social Aspects of the Poetry of Robinson Jeffers": holograph, [1926?] (Box 42, Folder 1303)
    - Flaccus, Kimball
      - "Fulton Fish Market": typescript, carbon, inscribed, 1941 Feb 2 (Box 42, Folder 1304)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee
      - "Abraca/dabra": typescript, original, signed, 1939 Mar 13 (Box 42, Folder 1305)
      - "After Reading White's Life of Shelley": typescript, carbon, signed, 1940 Oct 30
      - "Cebes to Phaedrus": typescript, carbon, signed, 1940 Mar 22 (Box 42, Folder 1306)
      - "Chapman at the Mermaid Tavern": typescript, carbon, signed, 1943 Apr 26
      - "Chronology": typescript, original, signed, 1940 Apr 23
      - "Compensation": typescript, carbon, [1939]
      - "Conversation on Olympus": typescript, original, signed, 1941 Feb 19
      - "A Dream": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 May 2
      - "Ed Campbell": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 Feb 7 (Box 42, Folder 1307)
      - "Fellatio": typescript, original, with notes "Fellow to the North Star": typescript, carbon, signed, 1940 Jan 26
      - "Gadara": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 Mar 4
      - "Hermaphroditus": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1937 Jun 17
      - "Hesperides": typescript, original and carbon, corrected, signed, 1943 Apr 27
      - "In Praise of Sleep": holograph, 1937 Aug 20 (Box 42, Folder 1308)
      - "Land's End": typescript, carbon, signed, 1938 Aug 23 (Box 42, Folder 1309)
      - "Letter to an Old Uncle": typescript, carbon, signed, 1939 Apr 13
      - "Medusa": typescript, original, corrected, annotated, signed, 1938 Jan 4 (Box 42, Folder 1310)
      - "Midnight Walk to the River": two drafts, typescript, original and typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, 1939 Aug-Sep
      - "The Moon Over Manhattan": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 Mar 9
      - "The New Atlantis Sinks": typescript, carbon, signed, 1941 Mar 23 (Box 42, Folder 1311)
      - "The Nightingale Sighs for the Moon's Bright Days": typescript, original, annotated and signed, 1940 Jun 5
      - "Ode On a Near Prospect of the University of Chicago": typescript, carbon, annotated, 1939 May 10 (Box 42, Folder 1312)
      - "The Peninsula": typescript, original, signed, 1939 Aug 23
      - "Plaques Old and New": typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, 1941 Mar 31
      - "Possession": holograph, signed, 1939 Jul 29 (Box 42, Folder 1313)
      - "Prince of this World": typescript, original, signed, 1939 May 1
      - "Raphael and Fornarina": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1943 Nov 3
      - "Sand Martins at Starved Rock": carbon, corrected, signed, 1941 Jan 18 (Box 42, Folder 1314)
      - "Shakespeare's Birthday 1939": typescript, carbon, signed, signed, 1939 Apr 23
      - "Sonnets by Puckett": typescript, original, 1938 Nov
      - "Sonnet to Arthur Ficke": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1941 Jan 21 (Box 42, Folder 1315)
      - "Starved Rock in Winter": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1941 Jan 21
      - "There is Labor Whither Thou Goest": typescript, original, signed, annotated, 1940 Mar 25 (Box 42, Folder 1316)
      - "The Tide Goes Out": typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, and annotated, 1940 May 24
      - "The Tractor": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 Apr 20
      - "The Triumph of Earth": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1940 Mar 11
      - "Why We Know Not": typescript, original, corrected, signed, 1939 Mar 29 (Box 42, Folder 1317)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent
      - "For Gladys and Eugene entreating them to take good care of Arthur": typescript, original, signed, 1927 Jan 8 (Box 42, Folder 1318)
      - "The Funeral": autograph manuscript in the hand of Arthur Davison Ficke, 1923 Aug 20 (Box 42, Folder 1319)
      - "Three Sonnets": typescript, original, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, [ca. 1918] (Box 42, Folder 1320)
      - [Untitled Sonnet]: autograph manuscript in the hand of Arthur Davison Ficke, 1923 Aug 20 (Box 42, Folder 1321)
    - Mitchell, Langdon
      - "Philosophical Dialogue...": holograph, 1927 (Box 42, Folder 1322)
    - Phipps, Elizabeth
      - "Song": typescript, carbon, signed, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 1323)
      - "Thirtieth June": typescript, carbon, signed, 1934
      - "To a Room Beloved": typescript, carbon, signed, 1934
      - "To One Absent": typescript, carbon, signed, 1934
      - "Yesterday's Gale": typescript, carbon, signed, 1934
    - Phipps, Katherine
      - "Southward Bound": holograph, 1939 (Box 42, Folder 1324)
    - Powys, John Cowper
      - A Glastonbury Romance: review, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1325)
      - [Review of Arthur Davison Ficke's The Secret and Other Poems ]: holograph by Gladys Brown Ficke, revised draft, [ca. 1936] (Box 42, Folder 1326)
    - Price, Robert
      - "Dead Girl: Saipan": typescript, original, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1327)
      - "The Sachem": typescript, original, with a note, n.d.
    - Roelvink, Herman C.
      - "The Stormbird": translated by Arthur Davison Ficke, printed version, 1913 (Box 42, Folder 1328)
    - [St. John Harbin?]
      - "Annabellemarie": 3 drafts, typescript, original and carbon (Box 42, Folder 1329)
    - Santayana, George
      - [Sonnet]: holograph, [ca. 1904-05] (Box 42, Folder 1330)
    - Sinclair, Upton
      - "What Can Be Done About America's Economic Troubles": printed version, 1939 (Box 42, Folder 1331)
    - Thomson, Raymond L.
      - "Saavedra": mimeograph, 1944 (Box 42, Folder 1332)
    - Watzek, Helene Ficke
      - "Family Episodes of Frances Davison Ficke and her parents": typescript, carbon, 1945 May (Box 42, Folder 1333)
    - Wilstach, John
      - "A Note on the Sonnets of Arthur Davison Ficke as Expressed by the Late Poet in a Letter to John Wilstach": printed version, annotated by John Wilstach, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1334)
    - Unidentified authors
      - "An Analysis by Tara Coleman": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1335)
      - "John Cowper Powys; His Universe": typescript, corrected, [1932?]
      - "[The Married Man]": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1336)
      - "Solitary-Husband": typescript, original
      - "Wail": typscript, original, annotated by Gladys Brown Ficke, 1945 Apr 21
      - Untitled poem: typescript, original, [1953?]
        With "In My Thirtieth Year" by Archibald Macleish, typescript.
- Photographs, 1865-1942; Series III; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Photographs, is arranged alphabetically by photographer or subject.
  - Adams, Ansel
    - "Aspen": inscribed to Arthur Davison Ficke, n.d.
    - "Monolith": signed, n.d.
    - "Robinson Jeffers": inscribed by Jeffers to Arthur Davison Ficke, 1928 Feb
    - "Snow": signed, n.d.
  - Aldis, Arthur: portrait by Hugh McKean, n.d.
  - Aldis, Mary Reynolds (2 portraits), n.d.
  - "Angelica": annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1337)
  - Browne, Maurice [Mr. Faust], 1914 (Box 43, Folder 1338)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1939 (Box 43, Folder 1339)
  - Carman, Bliss (5 photographs), n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1340)
  - Child, Edith Harlan, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1341)
  - China: photograph album, 1920
  - Davison, Ella, [ca. 1910] (Box 43, Folder 1342)
  - Davison, William, 1893, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1343)
  - Davison family, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1344)
  - Derre, Mary, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1345)
  - Devoe, Alan: signed, 1939 Sep 17
  - Evans, Grace, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1346)
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Frances Davison Ficke, [ca. 1884] (Box 43, Folder 1347)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1886 (Box 43, Folder 1348)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Alice Ficke, 1887 (Box 43, Folder 1349)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1889-94 (Box 43, Folder 1350-1351)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and the Davison family, [ca. 1895] (Box 43, Folder 1352)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1901-17 (Box 43, Folder 1353-1356)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Evelyn Blunt Ficke and Witter Bynner in Japan, 1917 (Box 43, Folder 1357)
    - Photograph by "Hostetter", 1917 (Box 43, Folder 1358)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1919 (Box 43, Folder 1359)
    - Photograph by "Grady", 1920 (Box 43, Folder 1360)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1921 (Box 43, Folder 1361-1362)
    - Photograph by the Macbride Studio, [ca. 1921] (Box 43, Folder 1363)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1923 (Box 43, Folder 1364)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Gladys Brown Ficke in France, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 1365)
    - Photograph by Witter Bynner in Santa Fe, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, 1927
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Witter Bynner, and Bliss Carman, Santa Fa, 1927
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Edna St. Vincent Millay, and Gladys Brown Ficke in Santa Fe, [ca. 1927]
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Gladys Brown Ficke, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 1366)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke: photograph by Witter Bynner, 1928
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 1367)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and John Cowper Powys, Santa Fe, [ca. 1928]
    - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, 1932 Nov 25 (Box 43, Folder 1368)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1369)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Gladys Brown Ficke, and Christine Hughes, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1370)
    - Photograph by Martin Hagget, 1934
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Alice Corbin, Mary Austin, Bliss Carman, Gladys Brown Ficke, Witter Bynner and Harry and Dorothy Harvey, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1371)
    - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, 1937 Dec 10 (Box 43, Folder 1372)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Louise Varèse, photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1937 Dec 10 (Box 43, Folder 1373)
    - Photograph by "Bouchard", 1938 (Box 43, Folder 1374)
    - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, 1938 Jan (Box 43, Folder 1375)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke, Gladys Brown Ficke, and Edgar Lee Masters, 1940 (Box 43, Folder 1376)
    - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, 1940 Feb 26 (Box 43, Folder 1377)
    - Photograph by Arnold Genthe, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 1378)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Gladys Brown Ficke, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 1379)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1380-1381)
    - Arthur Davison Ficke and Edna St. Vincent Millay (Box 43, Folder 1382)
    - Photograph by Ansel Adams, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1383-1384)
    - Photograph by Fabian Bachrach, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1385)
    - Silhouette by Johan Bull, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 1386)
    - Portrait by Rose O'Neill, n.d.
    - Four photographs of paintings by Bror Julius Olsson Norfeldt, n.d.
    - Photographs of portraits by unidentified artists, 1930, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1387)
    - Home movies of Arthur Davison Ficke, his wife, and Mr. and Mrs. Robinson Jeffers (Box cs, Folder 1387a)
  - Ficke, Bessy, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1388)
  - Ficke, Charles August, 1865-1928, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1389-1390)
    - Bust by Loredo Taft, 1926 (Box 43, Folder 1391)
    - Iowa Home, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1392)
    - Portrait by Andrew Dasburg (Box 43, Folder 1393)
  - Ficke, Mr. and Mrs. Christopher, 1860, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1394)
  - Ficke, Evelyn Blunt, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1395)
  - Ficke, Evelyn Blunt and Frances Blunt (Box 43, Folder 1396)
  - Ficke, Evelyn Blunt and Stanhope Blunt Ficke (Box 44, Folder 1397)
  - Ficke, Francis Davison, 1878-1914, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1398)
  - Ficke, Gladys Brown, 1915-27, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1399-1400)
    - Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, 1937 Dec 10 (Box 44, Folder 1401)
    - With Stanhope Blunt Ficke, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1402)
  - Ficke, Helene and Alice (Box 44, Folder 1403)
  - Ficke, Stanhope Blunt, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1404)
  - Ficke family
    - Switzerland, 1894 (Box 44, Folder 1405)
    - Africa, Egypt, and Jerusalem, 1896 (Box 44, Folder 1406)
    - Ficke family, 1904, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1407-1408)
    - Davenport, Iowa, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1409)
  - Flaccus, Kimball, 1940-41 (Box 44, Folder 1410)
  - Franke, Kuno, 1929 Jan (Box 44, Folder 1411)
  - French, Grace, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1412)
  - Genthe, Arnold
    - [Female nude seated], n.d.
    - [Female nude standing]
    - [Woman's hand holding jade]
  - Japan: photograph album, 1917
  - Jeffers, Robinson: 4 photographs by Arthur Davison Ficke, n.d.
  - Jeffers family, 1928 (Box 44, Folder 1413)
  - Kroll, Leon. Photograph by William McKillop of untitled painting, inscribed by Kroll to Gladys Brown, n.d.
  - Lundgren, Eric
  - Lundgren, Eric: [untitled photographs annotated in an unidentified hand] (Box 44, Folder 1414)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1415)
  - [O'Neil], Nance, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1416)
  - Phillpotts, Eden, inscribed to Arthur Davison Ficke, 1931 Jun
  - Praesant, Henriette, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1417)
  - Praesant, Johann Christain, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1418)
  - Prude family [Agnes De Mille], n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1419)
  - Rascoe, Ruth, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1420)
  - [Santa Fe], [ca. 1927]
  - Santayana, George (inscribed to Arthur Davison Ficke), 1923 (Box 44, Folder 1421)
  - Taos church photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1933 Jul 15
  - [Tauiris?], Helen, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1422)
  - Varèse, Edgar, inscribed to Arthur Davsion Ficke, 1924 (Box 44, Folder 1423)
  - Varèse, Louise Norton, photographed by Carl Van Vechten, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1424)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1425)
- Personal Papers, 1897-1968; Series IV; 3; (7 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, is organized into three groups relating to Arthur Davison Ficke, Gladys Brown Ficke, and the Ficke family. Each group is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Ficke, Arthur Davison
    - Aldis, Mary Reynolds, 1914, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1426)
    - Arrowheads, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1426a)
    - Art. Clipping on his, 1917 (Box 45, Folder 1426b)
      With note, holograph.
    - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1427)
    - Bills and receipts, 1903, 1933 (Box 45, Folder 1428)
    - Biographical information, 1914-51, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1429-1430)
    - Browne, Maurice, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1431)
    - Carman, Bliss, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1432)
    - Cartoons, 1917, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 1433)
    - Chapala, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1434)
    - Citation. République Française. Croix de Chevalier du Mérite agricole, 1919-20 (Box 45, Folder 1434a)
    - Complimentary copies list, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1435)
    - Copyright, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1436)
    - Diaries, 1896-1905 (Box 45, Folder 1437-1442)
    - Diaries, 1917-18 (Box 46, Folder 1443-1447)
    - Journals, 1933-36 (Box 46, Folder 1448-1455)
    - Diary: extracts, 1906-45 (Box 46, Folder 1456)
    - Notes and reflections, 1905-45 (Box 46, Folder 1457-1459)
    - Davenport High School certificate of promotion, 1897 Jun 23 (Box 46, Folder 1460)
    - Divorce, 1922 (Box 46, Folder 1461)
    - German currency, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 1462)
    - Gookin, Fredrick William, 1926 (Box 46, Folder 1463)
    - Harvard University diploma, 1904 Jun 29
    - Hesketh, 1943 (Box 46, Folder 1463a)
    - Japan, 1917 (Box 46, Folder 1464)
    - Japanese art, 1920-30 (Box 46, Folder 1465)
    - Juvenilia, 1892, 1903 (Box 46, Folder 1466)
    - Letters to the editor, 1924-36, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1467)
    - Marriage announcements, 1907, 1923 (Box 47, Folder 1468)
    - Marriage contract, 1923 (Box 47, Folder 1469)
    - Medication, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 1470)
    - Military papers. Appointment as Captain in the United States Army, 1917 Oct 12
    - Military papers. Appointment as Major in the United States Army, 1918 Jan 22
    - Military papers. Appointment as Lieutenant Colonel, United States Army, 1919 May 6 (Box 47, Folder 1471)
    - Military papers. Citation, United States Army, 1919 May 7
    - Military papers. Clippings, 1917-19 (Box 47, Folder 1472)
    - Military papers. Correspondence, 1917-20 (Box 47, Folder 1473)
    - Military papers. Discharge, 1919 Jul 13 (Box 47, Folder 1474)
    - Military papers. Identity papers, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1475)
    - Military papers. Miscellaneous, 1918, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1476)
      Includes three medals.
    - Military papers. Orders, 1917-19 (Box 47, Folder 1477-1479)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent. Clippings, 1928, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1480)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent. Contracts, 1923 Apr (Box 47, Folder 1481)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1482)
    - Obituaries, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 1483-1484)
    - Poetry, 1912-41, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1485)
    - Poetry Society reading, 1942 Mar 20 (Box 47, Folder 1486)
    - Powys, John Cowper, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1487)
    - Psychoanalytical notes: holograph and typescript, 1939 Jan-Apr (Box 47, Folder 1488-1496)
    - Santayana, George, 1944 (Box 47, Folder 1497)
    - Scrapbook, 1899 (Box 47a, Folder 1498)
    - Scrapbook, 1902-07 (Box 48, Folder 1499-1501)
    - Scrapbook, 1915-24 (Box 49, Folder 1502)
    - Scrapbook: Esquire short stories, 1924-40 (Box 49, Folder 1503)